Zuzana Knightova

London, NW3 and **Praha 6**zuzkaknight@yahoo.com
Mobile 07952 552 172

Summary

Having graduated with a BA degree in Conservation and Restoration, I re-joined the visual arts industry to rebuild my career after a long break to look after my children and specifically care for my, now adult and independent, disabled son. I have a strong track record in working in the visual arts. I am committed, hard-working, very organised, have strong office and IT skills and am an international person with good language skills.

Education

Front End Developer, EdX Bootcamp, London

December 2022 - March 2023

BSc in Conservation and Restoration of decorated surfaces on wooden or metal substrate, London Metropolitan University, London

part time study, from 2007- 2013

Work experience

Public Programme Manager, Art Academy London, London, August 2017 to November 2022

 Responsible for scheduling of nearly 400 primarily Fine Art courses annually and leading the Public Programme team in the subsequent planning, delivery, management and evaluation of the programme.

This includes managing the Public Programme budget; hiring tutors and managing long term relationship with them; communicating with Operations team to ensure smooth running of the programme; costumer care; student pastoral care, cooperation with the Marketing department as well holding responsibility for the Public Programme website section of the Art Academy site. 2 years ago, a new cloud software including AAL's new CRM system was introduced and I led the way in tailoring it to the AAL needs.

Organising Creative days for external companies

After Covid-enforced break in provision of Creative days, I am again leading communication with interested companies and group in our provision of team-building creative days.

- responsibility for running of the Newington Gallery (from August 2017 March 2020) and will be reintroduced in January 2023.
- Responsibility for overseeing the Art Academy's second campus at Newington (from August 2017 – March 2020).

This was put on hold from March 2020 until January 2023 due to Covid /National lockdown and will be reintroduced in January 2023 $\,$

Administrator, part time role at Art Academy London, London, September 2015 to August 2017

 Working in administration of public and academic courses at the Academy - The work included a variety of administrative responsibilities - processing bookings for courses, booking models for AAL courses, organising and keeping track of payments for models, responsibility for petty cash, ordering office supplies, responding to telephone enquiries; Secondly, I was a first point of contact for AAL students when they approached us with their enquiries. My role required me to respond and help students with their various requests where possible.

Work placement, HORNIMAN MUSEUM, London, 1st September to 31st October 2011

 Worked in the museum's conservation department – preventative conservation, object conservation, treatment and condition records, preparation of objects for exhibitions. Part of the team that delivered 'The Body Adorned' exhibition.

Care provider – London, from 2000 – 2015, at first fulltime Care provider, from 2007 part-time carer.

Deputy Director, IMAGE SERVICE, Prague, Czech Republic, February 1995 - October 1995

- Responsible for relationships with international photo libraries
- Built from scratch a new photo archive through cooperation with Czech photographers

Consultant to BRITISH COUNCIL curator Andree Cooke, Prague, Czech Republic, 1993-1995

- Oversaw communication with Czech artists
- Translation of written work concerning exhibitions at British Council's gallery

Gallery Deputy Manager, GALLERY MXM – Contemporary Art Gallery, Prague, Czech Republic, 1992-1995

- Responsible for gallery management, including organising exhibitions and maintaining relationship with in-house artists
- Front of house on sale of art

Assistance service officer, Ceska pojistovna, 1990 - 1991

 responsibility for individual accounts providing Assistance service to international visitors to Czecg republic

Projects/ Activities

Internship, Administrator, The Art Academy, London, 15th March 2015 - 16th July 2015

Daylight database, Google docs and others						

• Helped with administration of the Academy's courses - The work was based on

Volunteer education assistant, KENWOOD HOUSE, London, November 2013 to 2015

 Working with school groups during their visit to Kenwood House, concentrating on passing on information about history of the house and it's painting collections.

Freelance Assistant to Director, ArtKapsule, London, January 2014 - October 2014

- Working with the director during exhibition installations and de-installations, openings
- Consolidating and upgrading the database of the gallery

Bookkeeping assistant, Hampstead Knight, London, September 2013 to 2020

- bookkeeping
- communication with the company's accountants and HMRC

Training

- First Aid (2018)
- Fire Warden (2019)
- Mental Health First Aid (2020)

Completed e-training

- Data Protection
- Equality and Diversity
- The Prevent Duty
- Fire safety in Education
- Health and Safety in Education
- How to Effective Fire Warden or Fire Marshal
- Safeguarding Young People
- Number of other courses on EduCare platform

<u>Referees</u>

Upon request

Other

Born 1971, Prague, Czech Republic (moved to the UK in 1999)

Nationality Czech (with Sudanese heritage)

Family Husband and 4 children (24, 22, 20 and 15)

Languages Czech and English (fluent)

Interests I take a keen interest in disability issues.

To relax I like watching sci-fi films, reading, dress making, playing computer games.